Guide to the Sol Yurick Manuscripts for Publication TAM.268
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
Sol Yurick Manuscripts for Publication
1944-2001
TAM.268
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
43.0 linear feet 42 record cartons, 2 manuscript boxes, 1 folder in oversize
This collection consists principally of typed manuscripts and drafts written by novelist Sol Yurick (1925-2013). Yurick was a Brooklyn based writer whose novels shone a light on the poverty and violence in New York City in the 1960s and 1970s. The collection consists primarily drafts and manuscripts of Yurick's published works, but it also contains several manuscripts that were intended for but never reached publication. The collection also contains other materials related to the publication of his novels and stories, such as correspondence with publishers, contracts, and royalty statements. It also contains a small amount of personal items such as diaries, personal correspondence, and materials related to Yurick's teaching.
Yurick, Sol, 1925-2013
Box 1-43
Historical/Biographical Note
Sol Yurick (1925-2013) was an American author based in New York City, who was best known for novels portraying the grim realities of poverty and urban life in the 1960s and 1970s. Born in Manhattan on January 18, 1925, Yurick grew up in the Bronx where he attended the Bronx High School of Science. After high school he enlisted in the United States Army where he trained as a surgical technician during World War II. Yurick left the military in 1945 with a medical discharge due to an illness. Following his military service he enrolled in New York University on the GI Bill. At NYU pursued his interest in literature and graduated with a BA in English in 1951. He later received an MA in English from Brooklyn College.
Yurick worked for several years as an investigator for the New York City Department of Welfare. This experience left Yurick critical of the city's welfare bureaucracy, which he believed was designed to control rather than aid the city’s poor. Yurick’s first book, The Warriors, drew on his experience with the department of welfare and attempted to demonstrate that gang violence resulted from poverty rather than social dysfunction. Loosely based on the classical Greek story Anabasis, Yurick hoped the novel would provide a more accurate portrayal of gangs as a corrective to glamorized images in pop culture such as West Side Story. The Warriors was later turned into a motion picture in 1979, which garnered a strong cult following.
In the 1960s Yurick also became involved in the student protest movement and in the protests against the Vietnam War. Through his involvement he worked with Students for a Democratic Society and contributed the SDS tract, “Who Runs Columbia?”
After the 1960s Yurick became less involved in political activism, but continued to write. His other works include a collection of short stories titled Someone Just Like You (1972); an anthology titled Voices of Brooklyn (1973); and several novels including, An Island Death (1976), Richard A (1981), and Behold Metatron: The Recording Angel (1985). He also wrote several essays and short stories for the academic journal Social Text, which is published through Duke University Press.
Yurck lived in Park Slope, Brooklyn with his wife Adrienne. He died in January of 2013.
Arrangement
The order in which these materials were sent to the Tamiment Library has been maintained. Yurick's original titles have been maintained where possible.
Scope and Contents note
This collection principally consists of typed manuscripts of novelist Sol Yurick’s published and unpublished works. Yurick's writings include numerous drafts of his novels, essays, short stories, and plays. These manuscripts cover much of Yurick's career from his early writings in the mid-1940s to the early 2000s. This collection contains several versions of Yurick's drafts, which show the various stages of Yurick's writing process, and contain the author's edits and revisions. Many of the manuscripts in this collection eventually resulted in published versions, but the collection also contains a number of unpublished manuscripts.
The collection also contains a small number of materials related to Yurick's publications including correspondence with publishers, materials related to royalties, contracts, reviews, and documents related to film adaptations of Yurick's work. The collection also contains a small amount of personal items including correspondence with family and friends, journals, and materials related to Yurick's political activism.
Titles for the drafts and manuscripts in this collection have been maintained as best as possible. Many of these titles appear in abbreviated or alternate forms, which Yurick used throughout his editing process. The folder titles in the file list reflect these changes and abbreviations. Additionally, there are many cases in which the pages within Yurick's drafts appear out of order. Throughout the editing process, Yurick often included additional pages to his drafts or renumbered certain sections. Consequently, there are a number of instances where pages will appear to be repetitive, missing, or out of order. While this is partially reflective of Yurick's editing methodology, there are also a number of instances where loose drafts and fragments became out of order prior to being archived, the original order of which is difficult to discern.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Sol Yurick sent a gift his papers and manuscripts in 1985. The accession number associated with this gift is 1950.090. An additional twenty boxes of Yurick's papers were donated by Adrienne Yurick in 2014. The accession number associated with this gift is 2014.008.
Access Restrictions
Open for research without restrictions.
Yurick, Sol, 1925-2013; Yurick, Sol, 1925-2013; Essays.; Jewish radicals |z United States.; Manuscripts for publication.; Novelists, American |y 20th century.; Political fiction, American.; Short stories.
- "The Large Door", 1948-1965 (Box 1)
- Untitled Fragment, 1948-1949 (Box 1)
- "The Last S-F Story", 1948-1950 (Box 1)
- "Immolation: A Short Story", 1947-1950 (Box 1)
- "Companion of Virgil and Homer", 1947-1949 (Box 1)
- "The Lot of God", circa 1948-1949 (Box 1)
- "Schedule", circa 1940-1959 (Box 1)
- Various drafts-"The Flagellants," "Founders' Day", undated (Box 1)
- Untitled Fragment, 1947-1949 (Box 1)
- "Story of a Man Who Thought He Was Blind", 1947-1949 (Box 1)
- "Beauty and the Beast", 1947-1948 (Box 1)
- Untitled, undated (Box 1)
- "The Siege", undated; 3.0 folders 3 folders (Box 1)
- "The Anneling" (early version of the Noble Savage), undated (Box 1)
- "The Flight", circa 1958 (Box 1)
- Early Short Stories, undated (Box 1)
- "The Second Coming", undated (Box 1)
- Richard A, undated; 2.0 folders 2 folders (Box 1)
- "To Win Me Soon", 1944-1955, undated; 6.0 folders 6 folders (Box 1)
- Notes and Proposals, undated; 14.0 folders 14 folders (Box 2)
- Prototypes of Biography and Curriculum Vitae, undated (Box 2)
- "The Political Economy of Sexual Liberation", undated (Box 2)
- "Politics" (notes), undated (Box 2)
- Fertig, undated; 3.0 folders 3 folders (Box 2)
- The Bag (notes and edits), undated; 5.0 folders 5 folders (Box 2)
- "Counterintelligence for a Democratic Society" (notes and edits), undated (Box 3)
- "Disasters of a Summer's Hour The Pornography", undated (Box 3)
- "Fertig the Fulfillment", undated; 2.0 folders 2 folders (Box 3)
- "R.E. Project", undated (Box 3)
- "Critic of Capitalism Goes Hollywood" by Robert M. Berkman (article discussing film adaptations of Yurick's work), 2002 (Box 3)
- "The Awakening", undated (Box 3)
- "The Awakening" (early version), undated; 2.0 folders 2 folders (Box 3)
- "...And Not in Utter Nakedness...", May 15, 1964 (Box 3)
- "The Child-God Dance", Feb 15, 1962 (Box 3)
- "Someone Just Like Me", Mar 28, 1963, undated; 3.0 folders 3 folders (Box 3)
- "Do They Talk About Genet in Larchmont", undated (Box 3)
- "Welcome to the Tribe", undated (Box 3)
- "The Age of Gold", undated (Box 3)
- "The Big Greenout", undated; 2.0 folders 2 folders (Box 3)
- Sol Yurick Note Cards and Bound Typed Journal, 1963-1966, undated; 3.0 items 2 small boxes of Sol Yurick notes 1 bound volume containing Sol Yurick's typed journal (Box 4)
- Manuscripts - Correspondence, undated (Box 5)
- Manuscripts (fiction), undated; 6.0 folders 6 folders (Box 5)
- The Bag, undated; 2.0 folders 2 folders (Box 5)
- Untitled Manuscript, undated (Box 5)
- "Anabasis V", undated; 2.0 folders 2 folders (Box 5)
- "The Warriors", undated; 2.0 folders 2 folders (Box 5)
- Untitled Manuscript, undated; 2.0 folders 2 folders (Box 5)
- An Island Death, undated; 2.0 folders 2 folders (Box 5)
- "The Warriors", undated; 2.0 folders 2 folders (Box 6)
- Assorted Drafts and Political Writings, undated; 4.0 folders 4 folders (Box 6)
- "A Hunger for Dragons" Outline, undated (Box 6)
- Manuscripts (fiction), undated; 9.0 folders 9 folders (Box 6)
- "The King of Malaputa", undated; 7.0 folders (Box 7)
- Early session of the murders; Fertig; Later-"To Win Me Soon"; Early session of "The Biographical Novel", undated; 2.0 folders 2 folders (Box 7)
- "The Awakening", undated; 2.0 folders 2 folders (Box 7)
- "The Leaves and Fishes Program: Or; The Coming of the Cray III Christ", undated (Box 7)
- Assorted Drafts of Letters and Biographical Information about Yurick, undated (Box 7)
- "The Bridegroom Cometh" (fragment), undated (Box 7)
- Fertig (fragment), undated (Box 7)
- "The Age of Gold", Jan 9, 1965 (Box 7)
- "The Sound of One Hand Clapping", Jan 21, 1964 (Box 7)
- "Tarantella", Dec 1, 1962 (Box 7)
- "The Social Psychology of Lynching: A Story", May 2, 1962 (Box 7)
- "Founders Day", undated (Box 7)
- "...And Know Not Me", undated (Box 7)
- "Baron's Lost", undated (Box 7)
- Assorted Fragments, undated (Box 7)
- "Precis for a Detective Novel", undated (Box 7)
- Untitled Fragment, undated (Box 7)
- "Living off the Land", undated (Box 7)
- "Class in America", undated (Box 7)
- "Empire", undated (Box 7)
- "The Sticking Point", undated (Box 7)
- "The Second Coming", undated (Box 7)
- "Dear Child, I Feared That You Were Dead" (Box 7)
- "Behold the Metatron: The Recording Angel", undated; 5.0 folders 5 folders (Box 7)
- "The Harvesting", undated; 4.0 folders 4 folders (Box 8)
- An Island Death, undated (Box 1)
- The Bag, undated; 2.0 folders 2 folders (Box 8)
- "Death", undated (Box 8)
- "The Destiny Algorithm/Sound Money Kill", undated; 2.0 folders 2 folders (Box 8)
- "Faust as Stalin", undated (Box 8)
- "The Mutation of the Sociobeast", undated (Box 8)
- "The Hundred Gigaflop Snatch: A Treatment for a Screenplay", undated (Box 8)
- "The Fabulous Englishman" by Robert McCrum, Review by Yurick, undated (Box 8)
- "The Magic Kingdom" Stanley Elkins, "Dutton" Jerome Charyn, "War Cries Over Avenue C" Donald I. Fine, undated (Box 8)
- "The Art of Memory, Ancient and New", undated (Box 8)
- "Other People's Money: The Rise and Fall of OPM Leasing Services," Review by Yurick, undated (Box 8)
- "White Noise" by Don Delillo, Review by Yurick, undated (Box 8)
- "The One-Hundred Gigaflop Snatch: A Scenario", undated (Box 8)
- "The Hundred Gigaflop Snatch: A Scenario", undated (Box 8)
- "The Destiny Algorithm", undated; 2.0 folders 2 folders (Box 8)
- "Classets", undated (Box 8)
- "The Twenty Megaflop Dump-snatch", undated; 2.0 folders 2 folders (Box 8)
- "The King of Malaputa", undated; 2.0 folders 2 folders (Box 8)
- "Rosemyth", undated (Box 8)
- "The Loaves and Fishes Program", undated (Box 8)
- "The Harvesting", undated; 3.0 folders 3 folders (Box 8)
- "Sound Money Kill", undated; 3.0 folders 3 folders (Box 9)
- "To Win Me Soon-Final Version", undated; 3.0 folders 3 folders (Box 9)
- "The Bubble-Masters", undated (Box 9)
- "The Big Greenout", undated; 3.0 folders 3 folders (Box 9)
- "Burning", undated; 6.0 folders 6 folders (Box 9)
- "Burning-Part III", undated (Box 9)
- "Mission Control: Jesus? A Communist?", undated; 3.0 folders 3 folders (Box 9-10)
- "Purposes of Politics in the Imagination and an Outline", undated (Box 10)
- "Moby Dick as Politics and the New Novel", undated; 2.0 folders 2 folders (Box 10)
- "Politics in the Imagination: Burning the Bank of America", undated; 2.0 folders 2 folders (Box 10)
- "Burning the Bank of America", undated (Box 10)
- "The True Story of Oedipus", undated (Box 10)
- "Politics", undated; 3.0 folders (Box 10)
- "Burning", undated (Box 10)
- "In the Realm of the Angels", undated (Box 10)
- "Burning", undated; 4.0 folders (Box 10)
- "Some Comments on Parts 2 and 3", undated (Box 10)
- Journal, 1948 (Box 11)
- Journal, 1960-1963 (Box 11)
- Fertig (bound draft), undated (Box 12)
- Fertig (bound draft), undated (Box 13)
- "Politics in the Imagination", undated; 8.0 folders (Box 14)
- "Politics in the Imagination: The Problem of Consciousness and the Symbols of Domination", undated (Box 14)
- Handwritten Notes, Drafts, and Diagrams, undated; 3.0 folders (Box 14)
- Proposal for a Course, undated (Box 14)
- "The Big Greenout", undated; 2.0 folders (Box 14)
- Assorted Essays and Short Stories, 1968-1969; 3.0 folders (Box 14-15)
- An Island Death, undated; 4.0 folders (Box 15)
- An Island Death (galley proof), May 19, 1975 (Box 15)
- Someone Just Like You (proof), Feb 19, 1969; 2.0 folders (Box 15)
- An Island Death, undated; 3.0 folders (Box 15)
- "Jackie Marries Aristotle and Socrates Onassis: An Epithalamium" by The Gadfly, undated (Box 15)
- "The Political Economy of Drugs", undated (Box 15)
- "On Making Policy with Your Feet", undated (Box 15)
- "Towards a Revolutionary Literary Consciousness and the Hand of the CIA and FBI as Commissioner of Aesthetic Works", undated; 2.0 folders (Box 15)
- Richard A (master copy II), undated; 5.0 folders (Box 15-16)
- Behold the Metatron, The Recording Angel, undated; 2.0 folders (Box 16)
- "Project: The Harvesting", undated (Box 16)
- Manuscript for "Teshum-The Witness" by John Squire, May 30, 1984; 2.0 folders (Box 16)
- "Politics in the Imagination: Burning of the Bank of America", undated; 3.0 folders (Box 16)
- Letters and Correspondence: "Sound Money Kill", 1968-1980; 2.0 folders (Box 16)
- Correspondence, 1955-1984; 14.0 folders (Box 16-16A)
- "The King of Malaputa", circa 1991; 5.0 folders 5 folders (Box 17)
- Periodicals Containing Sol Yurick Articles: Bennington Review Winter 1969 and Cinecast Winter 1979-1980 (Box 17)
- Correspondence with Tetuso Kogawa, 1985-1995 (Box 17)
- Correspondence with Jan Pieterse, 1985-1991, undated (Box 17)
- Various Correspondence, Bulk, 1980-1990; 1977-2003; 3.0 folders 3 folders (Box 17)
- Various Pamphlets, 1978-1980, undated (Box 17)
- Various Materials Related to Freedom of Speech and Expression, 1968, 1981, undated (Box 17)
- Royalty Statements, 1975-1996, 2006 (Box 17)
- Correspondence with Doubleday, 1982, 1986-1990 (Box 17)
- Speaking Engagements, Honorariums, etc., 1985-1987, 1997 (Box 17)
- Postcards, 1963, 1983-1987 (Box 17)
- Correspondence with Georges Borchardt, 1985-2012 (Box 18)
- Correspondence with Yoshanan Lorwin, 1990-1993, 1999; 2.0 folders 2 folders (Box 18)
- Correspondence with Robert Coover, 1981-1998 (Box 18)
- Correspondence with Richard Carrier, 1998, 2002-2003 (Box 18)
- Teaching Material-Student papers, curriculum, etc., 1983, undated (Box 18)
- "Arthur" (assorted correspondence related to publications), 1975-1985 (Box 18)
- Correspondence from John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation, Jun 2, 1971-Jun 14, 1972 (Box 18)
- "Faust-Stages of Spiritual Economic Growth", undated (Box 19)
- "How the Athenians Planned...", undated (Box 19)
- Handwritten Notes and Questions "Malaputa", undated (Box 19)
- "OED Essay?", undated (Box 19)
- "OED Essay", 1994-1995; 3.0 folders 3 folders (Box 19)
- "Virgin Birth Meditations", May 2004-Oct 2004 (Box 19)
- "Paradise", Jul 2001-Sep 2001 (Box 19)
- "Age of Freemarket Metastate", undated (Box 19)
- "Age of Freemarket Metastate", undated (Box 19)
- "Political/Cultural Economy...", undated (Box 19)
- "Warriors as Allegory", undated (Box 19)
- "Warriors Essay", undated; 2.0 folders 2 folders (Box 19)
- "Marx/James", 2000-2006, undated; 5.0 folders 5 folders (Box 19)
- "Woodout", 1989-1994, undated; 6.0 folders 6 folders (Box 19)
- "Poli-OED", 1990-1994; 2.0 folders 2 folders (Box 19)
- "Faust" (Box 19)
- Articles and Newspaper Clippings- Reviews, 1965-1970; 2.0 folders 2 folders (Box 20)
- Articles and Ephemera- Political Activism, 1965-1986 (Box 20)
- Photographs from the 1979 Film adaptation of The Warriors (Box 20)
- "Moses Hall", undated; 2.0 folders 2 folders (Box 20)
- "ESI", Oct 1995-Dec 1995; 3.0 folders 3 folders (Box 20)
- "Deconstruction of Jews", 1990-1992; 4.0 folders 4 folders (Box 20)
- "OEDI Play", undated; 2.0 folders 2 folders (Box 20)
- "Suicide", Apr 1992-Sep 1992; 2.0 folders 2 folders (Box 20)
- "Short takes", 1989-2003; 6.0 folders 6 folders (Box 20)
- "Poli-Oed (Athenians)", 1996; 2.0 folders (Box 20-21)
- "Jews", Feb 1995-Mar 1995 (Box 21)
- "Burning of the Bank of America, or Politics in the Imagination of The Deconstruction of the Jews or The Blasted Cold-War Hearth", Feb 4, 1994-Feb 11, 1994 (Box 21)
- "Suicide", Aug 1,1991-Apr 11,1995 (Box 21)
- "How the Athenians Plotted to Infiltrate and Colonize the Mind of the West and Immortalize Themselves", Sep 19, 1996-Dec 10, 1996 (Box 21)
- "The Political Economy of the Imagination", undated; 2.0 folders 2 folders (Box 21)
- "Susanna Yurick"/"Consciousness", May 16, 2005 (Box 22)
- "Consciousness", undated (Box 22)
- "Loud," a novel by Russell T. Harrison, 1992 (Box 22)
- "The Religious Politics of the Delphic Priesthood" by Kevin Coogan, Jun 20, 1982 (Box 22)
- Article Recording Holocaust Museum, undated (Box 22)
- Sol's Highlighted Passages from Bible, undated (Box 22)
- "About Sid's Work" (essay in German by Wilfried Hulsemann), undated (Box 22)
- Works Sent to Saul, undated (Box 22)
- "Behold Metatron", undated (Box 23)
- "Metatron Speaks Again", Jan 1996-Mar 1996, undated; 3.0 folders 3 folders (Box 23)
- "Metatron Index?", undated (Box 23)
- "Metatron Speaks Again?", undated (Box 23)
- "Bank Burning", 1990-2003; 7.0 folders 7 folders (Box 23)
- "Burning", 1990-1994; 4.0 folders 4 folders (Box 23)
- "Burnout", May 1991-Jun 1991 (Box 23)
- "Destiny of Algorithm", 1992-1994; 3.0 folders 3 folders (Box 23)
- "European", May 1994 (Box 23)
- "Destiny of Algorithm Paradise", undated (Box 23)
- "Destiny of Algorithm Reshuffled", Jun 2000 (Box 23)
- "Destiny of (Pre) Algorithms", Dec 2002, undated; 2.0 folders 2 folders (Box 23)
- "Destiny of Algorithm Preconditions", undated (Box 23)
- "Euroiden", 1991-1993; 6.0 folders 6 folders (Box 24)
- "Eucharist", May 2004 (Box 24)
- "Reply to George", undated (Box 24)
- "Joseph", Dec 1989 (Box 24)
- "Bereshit/Great Escape", undated (Box 24)
- Personal items including Birth Certificate and Military Records, undated (Box 24)
- Ms. Magazine, May 1977 (Box 25)
- "The Political Economy of Literature", undated; 2.0 folders 2 folders (Box 25)
- Notes and Articles Related to Telecommunications, undated (Box 25)
- "Reply to Letter by George", undated (Box 25)
- "Memories in the Context of the End of the Cold War", undated (Box 25)
- "In the Paradise Theater", Jul 30 2001-Aug 2, 2001 (Box 25)
- "Marx and James Meet in the Ahistorical Garden of Innocence", Aug 30, 2000 (Box 25)
- "Short Takes", May 29, 2001-Sep 19, 2002 (Box 25)
- "The Destiny of Algorithm, Or: The King of Malaputa, Or: A Hunger for Dragons", Jun 14, 2000 (Box 25)
- Personal Items (includes address books, one art book, and an unlabeled photograph), undated (Box 25)
- "Marxist Detective Novel", undated; 2.0 folders 2 folders (Box 25)
- Papers Miscellaneous Current, undated (Box 25)
- Miscellaneous Letters Current, undated; 2.0 folders 2 folders (Box 25)
- "Malaputa", undated; 16.0 folders (Box 26)
- "Malaputa", undated; 17.0 folders (Box 27)
- "Malaputa", undated; 17.0 folders (Box 28)
- "Malaputa", undated; 10.0 folders (Box 29)
- "Lecture-discussion", undated (Box 29)
- "Faust/Yurick" - Manuscript "Faust's Stages of Spiritual/Economic Growth and Take off into Transcendence", undated (Box 29)
- "Faust/Yurick", undated; 2.0 folders 2 folders (Box 29)
- "Understanding the Context of the Iranagua or Iran-contra Conspiracy", undated (Box 29)
- "Faust's Stages of Spiritual/Economic Growth and Take off into Transcendence", undated; 2.0 folders 2 folders (Box 29)
- "Faust", undated; 3.0 folders 3 folders (Box 29)
- "Malaputa", undated (Box 30)
- "The Big Greenout", undated; 17.0 folders 17 folders (Box 30)
- "Green Outline/Delbert", undated (Box 30)
- "Delbert and the Witch World of St. Cunegonde", undated (Box 30)
- "Directory Listing of C:\Malout", undated (Box 31)
- "Wooden O/Within this Wooden O", undated (Box 31)
- "Malaputa", undated; 4.0 folders 4 folders (Box 31)
- "Suite Vengeance (with Dobson and Quigley)", undated (Box 31)
- "Dionysus at the Beach (with Dobson and Quigley)", undated (Box 31)
- "The Concert at the Beach (with Dobson and Quigley)", undated (Box 31)
- "Oedipus", 1988-1989; 6.0 folders 6 folders (Box 31)
- "The Future of the Information Age", undated (Box 32)
- "Within this Wooden O", undated (Box 32)
- Review of "The Postmodern Aura" by Charles Newman, undated (Box 32)
- "The Library", undated (Box 32)
- "Picexhib", undated (Box 32)
- "Information, The Future, Technopolitical Economics and Nationalism", undated (Box 32)
- "The Situation Room Concept of Malaputa", undated (Box 32)
- "Oediplay", undated; 2.0 folders 2 folders (Box 32)
- "Why Oedipus?", undated (Box 32)
- "What Really Happened to Oedipus and How it Affected our Lives", undated (Box 32)
- "Outline for a Series of Linked Essays to be Tentatively Called 'Politics in the Imagination'", undated (Box 32)
- "The Future of the Information Age", undated (Box 32)
- "The Coming of the Technologization of Art", undated (Box 32)
- "Outline for a novel tentatively to be called The Wooden O.", undated (Box 32)
- "The Wooden O. Continued", undated (Box 32)
- "How the Athenians Planned to Trick Freud and Colonize the Mind of the West and Immortalize Themselves aka 'Oediplay'", undated; 2.0 folders 2 folders (Box 32)
- "On Joseph in Egypt's Model for an Agricultural Revolution", undated (Box 32)
- "On the Deconstruction of the Jews", undated (Box 32)
- "Malaputa", undated; 6.0 folders 6 folders (Box 32)
- "Gangs, Crews, Posses, Prides and Exaltations", Sep 29,1990-Oct 1,1990 (Box 33)
- "Invitation to a Bank Burning", 1990; 3.0 folders 3 folders (Box 33)
- "On the Deconstruction of the Jews", 1990-1991; 5.0 folders 5 folders (Box 33)
- "The Emergence of the Metastate versus Identity Politics", Apr 18, 1990-Apr 27, 1990 (Box 33)
- "How the Athenians Planned to Trick Freud and Colonize the Mind of the West and Immortalize Themselves", undated (Box 33)
- "Within this Wooden O.", 1989; 4.0 folders 4 folders (Box 33)
- "Oediplay", Sep 8, 1989-Sep 21, 1989 (Box 33)
- "On Sports, Gambling and Steroids", undated (Box 33)
- "Suicide", 1991-1992; 3.0 folders 3 folders (Box 33)
- "Oedipus: Or The Coup: Or The CIA Oedipus", Jan 9, 1992-Jan 22, 1992 (Box 33)
- "Burning", 1990-1991; 4.0 folders 3 folders in Box 33 1 folder in Box 34 (Box 33-34)
- "Euroiden", 1991; 4.0 folders 4 folders (Box 34)
- "Suicide", 1991; 3.0 folders 3 folders (Box 34)
- "Invitation to a Bank Burning", 1990; 3.0 folders 3 folders (Box 34)
- "Poli-Oed", Oct 23, 1989-Aug 19, 1990 (Box 34)
- "The Deconstruction of the Jews", May 18, 1990-May 22, 1990 (Box 34)
- Untitled Outline, undated (Box 34)
- "The King of Malaputa", undated; 5.0 folders (Box 34)
- "The King of Malaputa", undated; 20.0 folders (Box 35)
- "The King of Malaputa", undated; 15.0 folders (Box 36)
- "Green", undated; 3.0 folders 3 folders (Box 36)
- "Devlin's Trip into the 'Interior'", undated (Box 36)
- "Later Dreams", undated (Box 36)